<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>The Journey</title>
  <slug>the-journey</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-05-22 17:09:21</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;So the flight from Vancouver&amp;nbsp;was fairly uneventful. I got on, the seat next to me wasn't taken so I was pretty comfortable. I didn't take as many pictures (or any I think) from the plane because we immediately way up high and there was nothing to see. I watched a couple movies: one Chinese with subtitles, two English (with no subtitles). I resisted the urge to watch the second hunger games again. Love me some Jenifer&amp;nbsp;Lawrence.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to Hong&amp;nbsp;Kong, my baggage was all accounted&amp;nbsp;for ,customs was a breeze. I exchanged some currency (Not nearly enough as it turns out) and was on my way on the train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thoughts on the Metro Train:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I've been out of customs 5 minutes and I already think I got screwed by someone. I think I bought a metro pass that I didn't need. Thanks currency exchange people.&amp;nbsp;OOOO wait."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remembered you swipe when you go out of a Chinese subway station. Thanks helpful currency exchange lady I would have paid a cabby 太多钱.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then got out of the subway and was welcomed by a giant Chinese mall. BOOOOOOO. What was worse is that for the life of me I couldn't find an exit that wasn't a "car park" or a taxi pick up. Struggles. So I ended up taking a $40 HKD&amp;nbsp;cab ride aproximately&amp;nbsp;5 blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which worked out in my favor because the doorway to the sketch elevator that took me to the hostel was what I would describe as nondescript. I'm not sure I would have found it had I not been dropped off close and known that I was within 15 feet of it. I still almost missed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"So it goes" (I will give credit it where credit is due on this once and will continue to use it all of the time under the assumption that everyone will know who said it) - Kurt Vonnegut&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First impression of Hong&amp;nbsp;Kong. Too many English speakers. The cab drivers speak English but maybe it's just this area I'm in. I get here and the place is a giant shopping mall. The subway station was a mall my hostel is in a mall. Hong Kong = giant mall? Also nothing is cheap, not cool Hong&amp;nbsp;Kong. Not Cool. But I have only been here for like 6 hour. So I really have "Nothing to Declare"&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's 1:25 AM Beijing mandated time zone time, I am wide awake. Jet lag is a real problem people. Good After-noo-ight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>