<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Once Again, Wifi Access and Time on the road small</title>
  <slug>once-again-wifi-access-and-time-on-the-road-small</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-07-03 00:45:10</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;To give a quick update, I am heading out into the grasslands and the dessert this morning. I am going on a one night two days trip with the hostel I am staying at in 呼和浩特. (Hohhut&amp;nbsp;Inner Mongolia).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before here I was in Lan Zhou. I may have set a tourist record for most photos taken, somewhere in the neighborhood of 1000. When you are traveling alone and you have a fairly new camera, there seems to be not much else worth doing. Also I am finding that I really enjoy photography. It takes going for a walk or sightseeing, a sometimes quite boring activity into something challenging. I always have my eye open looking for the next good shot. Yes, it does cause you to see much of what you are seeing from through the viewfinder of your camera. As long as one takes a break from it, and admires with just their eyes what is around them the experience is as good or better as without a camera in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More thoughts later; when I get to Beijing I will have a moment to breath, reflect, upload images and fix that image page that keeps breaking (I keep breaking).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-----&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update for any of you who care. I am currently working on getting up the posts and photos from the last few days. I have been fighting some technical issues, basically meaning I mess some stuff in my code up. That part is fixed. I am also fighting some weird issues uploading my style sheets so if you see things not looking quite right, just ignore it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>