<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Inaugural Post</title>
  <slug>inaugural-post</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-05-21 13:06:39</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;So here I am: I am in two places one for the first, one for the second. I am for a second time sitting in O'Hare airport waiting on a flight to go to China. I am for my first time in any real capacity on the internet. From hence forth I am JacksonJHayes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;On my mind that I didn't very much think about was, what exactly am I going to do on the over 15 hours of flights that I am going to be on "today." Today being a funny way to put it because It will be about 30 hours of being awake, and a large time zone change. I have downloaded a book onto my phone to read, "Beyond Good and Evil" by Nietzsche, which is so typically me. I also have my project which I almost completely forgot that I was working on that I could dabble with, my chess engine. So that might happen, I can't imagine that my brain is exactly sharp enough to get much of that done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;The next question really is, what am I going to do when I land. I have a hostel booked, but there is some problem with the website that I booked it with. That is a bit disconcerting but I will try not to worry, and in the spirit of this trip I will say this, and hopefully never say this phrase on this blog ever again, #Yolo. (Also to steal a phrase from a Erin, long hair don't care.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;In my ears as has been for more or less the last week straight is Regina Spektor--Simple, beautiful, comfortingly familiar, hopeful. Just what I need right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;When I got to the airport I displayed just how inexperienced of an air traveler I am. I got to the check-in area and I was told that I was in the wrong place because it was an "American Airlines" flight operated by West Jet--whatever. I got to West Jet and I mistakenly thought I could remotely hope that my giant backpack could be a carry on--ya right. I put my bag on the scale and it was 15 pounds overweight. They told me to move some of it to my almost empty carry on / personal bag. The reweighed and I was fine. I thought I was done so I started walking away, nope. They don't take the bag there, Luggage tags and move somewhere else to drop it off. (I'll chalk that one up to it being 5:45 in the morning.) Then they said move whatever you want back into the big bag-&lt;em&gt;okay&lt;/em&gt;. Everything else has seemed to go smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Last thought before I board my plane to Vancouver no one looks good at an airport, especially in the morning. Therefore selfies for everyone. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>