<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Update From Previous Post</title>
  <slug>update-from-previous-post</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-06-16 02:47:20</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;So I was incorrect, I was not going to my host stay Dad's Father's day dinner. I actually went to my home stay mother's father's dinner. We went to a lovely Buddhist restaurant. I didn't catch if the Grandpa is Buddhist or if he, and some of the other members of the family, "don't eat meat a lot." (loosely translated)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Upon returning home from dinner the Grandma pulled a set of keys out of her pocket and started unlocking the door. (If you don't know why this is a big deal read previous posts.) So I asked, "is the door broken?" My home-stay mother replied that since the door is wooden, when it rains the door expands and it can't shut all the way. (Do not be impressed with my level of Chinese, I extrapolated this from some very simple sentences with my cursory knowledge of physics.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;So this ends the mystery of the weird home-stay locking strategy. Now on to figuring out whether the home-stay mom and dad are separated or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Evidence against:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;When he is here they share the same room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;When he is here he walks around the place like he owns it. Presumably he does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;They seem very relaxed around each other (the two times I have seen them in the same room.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;I asked her a question or two about her husband and she didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to hesitate (I talk as if I would notice if she did if she did)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;It doesn't really make sense that they would be separated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Evidence for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Home-stay brother did not go to dinner with his dad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;The dad is never home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Home-stay mom didn't tell him that I was going to be living in the house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;He lives somewhere else Monday-Friday, usually, with his parents and the daughter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Something just feels entirely off about the house, the family situation, the brother seems to me as if he was raised without a strong father figure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;If you don't want your family situation evaluated in such detail, don't invite strangers to live with you That, or don't get married. But mostly the not letting stranger's live in your house and give them Internet&amp;nbsp;access.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>