<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Last Week in Guilin</title>
  <slug>last-week-in-guilin</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-06-28 12:15:43</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Last week was my final week at&amp;nbsp;CLI. I went about my normal routine, I got up fairly early in the morning and headed to&amp;nbsp;CLI&amp;nbsp;when I was ready. I had classes, studied, played ping pong, watched movies etc. until returning to my home-stay rather late in the evening.&amp;nbsp;I am racking my brain for anything worth remembering or sharing, but nothing is really coming to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final day in&amp;nbsp;Guilin&amp;nbsp;was one of the best. My teacher&amp;nbsp;Klock&amp;nbsp;and I had made plans to go hang out at his favorite tea house and get lunch afterwards. It was an awesome insight into the life of a Chinese hippie. He seems to lead a very simple, yet particular and&amp;nbsp;meticulous&amp;nbsp;life. Everything he does in a unhurried and thought filled manner. At his tea favorite tea house I got to make tea with a proper tea set for the first time-very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For lunch we ate at a vegetarian buffet style restaurant inside of a Buddhist temple. I think it was the same restaurant that I ate at with my homestay family for father's day. The food was good, but more importantly clean. I have noticed this phenomenon before in China, people with dietary restrictions, especially for religious reasons, whether or not it tastes good it is always clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch we walked around the parks near where we were. This was almost painful for me at first because of how slow Klock walks. As any of you who have walked anywhere with me before know, my normal walking pace is a jogging pace for some people. However, after slowing myself down it was a relaxing way to spend my last afternoon in Guilin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we walked so slow, and I forgot a flash drive that I borrowed from my friend Archer and had to go home, I was late for my afternoon class by about a half an hour. This ended up not being a big deal, especially since Kiki and I spent the rest of the class just chatting (in Chinese of course).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night CLI took us out for a "farewell dinner." There were four other students who were leaving CLI that weekend. There were at least 25 people that came to dinner. It was a 老外 invasion. Dinner was family style, and I really didn&amp;rsquo;t quite get enough food, mostly because many of the dishes were far to spicy for me. When eating my first or second bit of food I pulled the food from my chopsticks when I meant to bite it. I was rewarded for that mistake by having spicy oil splash into my eyes. My first thought, "Oh Lord I have blinded myself eating spicy food!" And now I have a new reason to fear spicy food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After everyone made their goodbye speeches (again in Chinese) we all slowly left the restaurant. There was about fifteen to twenty minutes of indecision about where to go or what to do. One group went back to CLI. One group wanted to go walking around the lakes. Which makes the situation sound more simple than it was. It was a quagmire. Eventually I made back to CLI, via the group walking around the lake and a cab drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to CLI and not home because I forgot to say goodbye to Jake and I told Sunny that we would have a rematch before I left. I won the grudge match. Afterwards everyone went out to a bar. I really wanted to not, but not doing things with people is not part of my life philosophy right now. So I went. It was a very typical Americans and Chinese people together at a bar. We played liar's poker, they drank Budweiser, I drank water from my Nalgene. We all headed out around 12:30, I hopped on the back of Jeffery's scooter, after waiting a couple minutes for him to finish his beer. (Yes that worried me a little too, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to walk the mile or so to my homestay. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment it occurs that I even find this rambling on about the minor details of my days rather boring. I hope it is boring to me only because I am the one who has lived these aforementioned days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;*If you find would like to file a complaint about&amp;nbsp;the aforementioned blog, please email us at notgoingtoread@jacksonjhayes.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Continuing on with the story of going to bed, there was of course one final battle that must be waged. That battle of course was the battle with the door locking shoe lace. This battle ended up being quite a struggle. Whoever tied it knew what they were on about. It was a twenty minute 5 or 6 round battle. I almost threw in the towel in the 4th round but I persevered and prevailed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>