<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Shanghai the Quick Version</title>
  <slug>shanghai-the-quick-version</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-07-13 11:04:54</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;I had no real plans for Shanghai other than hanging out with Aimee's brother Chris. Highlights of the city:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The foreign&amp;nbsp;language book store. It was basically a whole floor of just goods. Seemly only divided into two categories: old books and new books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tourist fake goods market. Unlike the ones in Beijing the prices started out at a reasonable price and no one is screaming the only three English words the know at you. (You by beats!?!?!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pool table in the hostel lounge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tianzifang (田子坊) a cool little old neighborhood that they gentrified. Everything was pricy but it was just a cool little spot. My vintage sunglasses I bought from a 时髦 little shop made the trip worthwhile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hanging out with Chris, a budding 中国通 / a very interesting&amp;nbsp;person to listen to talk. He probably thought that his showing me around Shanghai was lack luster but aimlessly walking and talking to someone interesting is what I would rather be doing any day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The low point: &lt;br /&gt;I was hanging out with a Canadian girl from the hostel named Brit. She had never had Lanzhou hand pulled noodles so we went to a place that we saw on our way to the bookstore. While we were sitting waiting for our food a cute little kitty walked up. I instinctively started petting the back of his neck. I petted him for a couple seconds until I saw the most disturbing thing I have ever seen, I am probably not exaggerating. The cat around his back hip had an actual hole. The only way to describe what it looked like was the hole in Two-Face's face in The Dark Knight movie. You could see muscle, you could see what looked like a bone. My entire being froze, body and soul. I thankfully didn&amp;rsquo;t touch the wound or the surrounding area. However, it was startling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was unbelievable but the cat was totally ok. Even though the wound was open, it wasn't bleeding. It had some disgusting scabby looking black things. If I had a wound like that I would be freaking out at all times, day and night until the situation was resolved or I died of exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing that set me over the edge was the fact that after I went white as a ghost and yelled at the cat to go away the 老板呀 asked me if I was afraid of cats. I said no. In my head and to Brit I said, NO I AM NOT AFRAID OF CATS, I AM HOWEVER AFRAID OF INFECTIOUS DISEASES FROM THE OPEN WOUND IN THE SIDE OF THE CAT AND THE FACT THAT, THAT DISEASE TRAP OF AN ANIMAL JUST WALKED CASUALLY INTO YOUR KITCHEN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ate the noodles and they were great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>