<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>I have said to many people this is the way to learn programming.</title>
  <slug>i-have-said-to-many-people-this-is-the-way-to-learn-programming</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-06-19 01:33:53</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;In Paris a tech-entrepreneur-billionaire&amp;nbsp;is starting a college specifically designed to pump out highly qualified programmers and here's how:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The basic idea of &amp;Eacute;cole 42 is to throw all the students &amp;mdash; 800 to 1,000 per year &amp;mdash; into a single building in the heart of Paris, give them Macs with big Cinema displays, and throw increasingly difficult programming challenges at them. The students are given little direction about how to solve the problems, so they have to turn to each other &amp;mdash; and to the Internet &amp;mdash; to figure out the solutions."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long version:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://venturebeat.com/2014/06/13/this-french-tech-school-has-no-teachers-no-books-no-tuition-and-it-could-change-everything/"&gt;Souce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many things that you learn from a Computer Science degree at a traditional University. I certainly wouldn't be as knowledgeable about many aspects of computing theory or practive if I didn't attend Loyola. I was the type of person who thrives in a University environment. I need structure,I needed the variety of course work, I need the comfort of it.&amp;nbsp;However, I&amp;mdash;and others like me&amp;mdash;could learn programming so much faster if allowed to just go off and let the Internet guide them. I would argue that this is how everyone learns programming anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prove that I recieved a liberal arts education I will quote Plato: "and yet a true creator is necessity, which is the mother of our invention."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you throw motivated people in a room with a computer and a problem, necessity will cause them to use what they know and research what they don't already know, necessity will cause them to try and fail, failure will drive them to obsession, and the whole process ultimately will cause them to learn.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then they will get up the next morning and do it all over again&amp;mdash;or drink a cup of coffee and keep going if obsession kept them up all night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model that they have created wouldn't work for every type of education or for every type of person. However, it begs the question, is it time to rethink how we educate our children, our high school students, people attending universities? Or more importantly, should we rethink how we want to educate ourselves?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>