<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>First Day in Guilin Part 2</title>
  <slug>first-day-in-guilin-part-2</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-05-27 22:23:22</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Lots of surprises today. First, my school is much nicer than I expected. I expected it to be in some building on one of the college campuses here. However, it actually is its own building. The amenities are very nice, IT HAS AN ELECTRIC PIANO (which is a big deal for me)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.199999809265137px;"&gt;A short aside: I wanted to play a little and Nancy the girl who was giving me my orientation listened to me play with some other people. She thought I was quite good. Fair enough at this point I can concede&amp;nbsp;that I am not bad at piano, even though I used to think I was not good at all. However, later I sat down to play on the headphones by myself and a bunch of the Chinese girls came up and asked if they could listen. So I begrudgingly&amp;nbsp;obliged even though I don't particularly like to perform.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.199999809265137px;"&gt;There are so many ways to describe what happened, and most of them are inappropriate. The best way to describe it, I guess, is to say they swooned over me. They all said that I was very handsome (the word 帅 doesn't translate very well) but it was a bit odd to hear nonetheless.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.199999809265137px;"&gt;The next surprise for the day was that my Chinese is not as bad as I thought it would be. I thought I would have forgotten a lot, but some how I feel like it is better than when I left Beijing, which makes no sense whatsoever. I am actually already struggling to write in English because my brain is fighting to translate to Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.199999809265137px;"&gt;After a long day at the school building (mostly playing ping pong) I went to dinner with some new friends Jake and Miguel (jewish&amp;nbsp;pronciation). After that I walked towards my&amp;nbsp;homestay, when I arrived (a small miracle that I didn't get lost) my host sister was going out to meet her friends for some drinks so I went with them. That was an experience. At one point, because I said that I find China interesting, they suggested that I get a Chinese girlfriend. They asked if I understood what they were saying. I said something to the effect of "I think I understand, but I will say that I don't."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.199999809265137px;"&gt;Xie&amp;nbsp;Jie&amp;nbsp;(host sister) walked me home, when I got to bed I thought it must be at least midnight, wrong. Not even 10:30. Now I sleep.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>