<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Arrival in Qingdao</title>
  <slug>arrival-in-qingdao</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-07-07 17:01:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Sitting on the bullet train I am feeling weary of the road. I have covered a lot of ground soon, met some great people and seen some things that will probably take a while to realize how amazing they were. I am missing home. I miss familiar faces and family. I have not been able to get a reliable internet connection at the correct time to skype anyone since I left Guilin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to this I have decided that I the next couple of days I am going to be lazy, relax, go to the beach if the weather is comfortable and just recuperate. I have no plans of doing anything that isn't easy, will require me to walk long distances, deal with sleazy 面包车 fake cab drivers or do anything particuarly Chinese. Maybe I will do some Chinese studying so I don't get completely out of the habit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the train car, they are now playing what seems to be a documentary about Hayao Miasaki and Studio Ghibli. Having just bought quite a few of his movies it seems like he is following me. Maybe to make me feel guilty for buying from a store clearly selling pirated DVD's. 这是中国.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about the photos that I have taken for the video I plan to make to document my experience on my trip I have come up with a working title. Put your head down and go, pick your head up and see where you are, look back and see how far you've come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the parents on the train smacked their child, I don't know why, and then the child proceeded to start crying. The parent then shushed the child in an attempt to get the child to quit crying, because that makes sense. Start them crying and then tell them they can't cry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scene got me thinking about childhood and how one puts a child in time out. A time out really isn't much of a real punishment. It is more about the idea that you are being punished. It works fairly well on children who don't really understand the concept of what is going on in the situation. When we grow up we have to be punished in more real ways. However, don't think I really ever grew out of this phase. The very idea of being in trouble, or someone being angry with me when it is at all my fault, can trouble still terrifies me and can throw me into debilitating anxiety. In spite of all my pretending to seem or act older than my age throughout my life I can now confirm I am-- and have the mind of--a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Then some time passes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have now arrived at my hostel and am sitting in the stairwell common area writing blog content and uploading pictures. There is a small child behind me, being noisy as children are. I am apparently very tired, cranky and sick of noisy children today because he is getting on my nerves far more than he should be. Small children's shrill voices are not what I am looking am expecting in a hostel. And as I am sitting here writing the mom of the child waves to me and sets a sucker down in front of me. I don&amp;rsquo;t understand life. I just don't get it. The watermelonly goodness is helping me cope.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>