<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Red Eye Flight to Shanghai</title>
  <slug>red-eye-flight-to-shanghai</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-07-12 01:30:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;After a red eye plane from Qingdao I have arrived in Shanghai. As we were landing I was fast asleep in my seat leaning against the window. The plane jarred me awake just in time for me to feel us drop toward the ground at the last second and then hit the ground. I thought we were still in mid-flight and we hit bad turbulence and I had slept through my last moments on this sweet earth. Luckily nothing of the sort was the case and we then gently rolled into the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I waited for my baggage a six or seven year old child was being dragged by his mother across the terminal from our flight. One who doesn't speak Chinese would think that he was having his arm pulled off or someone was kidnapping&amp;nbsp;him (it is worth noting here that I am exaggerating slightly here, it was 12:30 pm and I did not want to be awake.) In fact what he was screaming was "Sleep Sleep, I want to sleep" and then he would just make a bunch of whining noises. I can only imagine how the mom felt. She was at arm's length from the little noise box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After successfully grabbing my bag and getting out of the terminal I only had one thing left to do for the night. Find a bed to sleep in. A hotel seemed like the best choice so I picked my head up and looked for hotels. I saw a couple about 200-300 yards off so I walked in that direction. As I was walking into the first one a lady walking around with an old dingy bike asked me if I needed a hotel and she would take me to one for 100 kuai. Two thoughts: first, no thanks creepy lade hanging outside the hotel with a bike, I enjoy the use of all of my organs; second, I don't need your help and good luck getting me on that bike with my 60 pounds of backpacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I proceeded past the creepy lady and into the hotel. I walked up to the desk and asked how much the cheapest room was, after clicking away at the computer she told me 500 kuai was the cheapest. Seeing how that was about 400 more than I would like to pay on an average night I asked her to point me in the direction of a cheaper hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She told me to just walk down the street for three minutes. It ended up being only like 200 yards but she clearly saw how much stuff I was carrying and decided to overestimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked into this hotel, same routine as before, but this time 200 kuai. Again too much, but I was tired and for less than fifty dollars I was just ready to be in bed so I paid the money and slept. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>