<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Getting The Hang of China</title>
  <slug>getting-the-hang-of-china</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-06-24 00:00:56</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Some days you feel like China is an insurmountable force. I sometimes feel like I just get my ass handed to me on a daily basis by China. Today I feel like I am getting at least competitive with China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first key ingredient is a positive attitude, and truly I don't have reason to not have one. I woke up in a decidedly good mood. I didn't engage my homestay&amp;nbsp;family, and just went about my business. Well maybe I could have a bad attitude, that is always an option, I'll let you be the judge of this weekend / today and whether I should be able to complain.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past weekend is to be my last in Gui Lin so I decided that I wanted to go to Yang Shou, which is a touristy city in Gui Lin county. There are lots of hostels, bars, western restaurants etc. The plan was to go Friday night and stay until Sunday evening. China had other plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told my homestay mother my plans, and her response was, that sounds great, but how about I ruin those plans for you. I want to "出去玩" (to go out and have fun) on Sunday. I said ok that sounds fine I can be home Sunday morning. She replied, no if we want to do what I have planned we have to leave Sunday morning. I told her that I would ask my friends. She gave no explanation&amp;nbsp;of what we were going to do. So of course I was skeptical.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came back that evening and again asked what her plan was, no response given. Just asked if I wanted to go or not. I agreed, and said that I would return Saturday night.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Friday night after class my plan was to leave directly after class. My friend Jake, however, wanted to go to the farewell dinner for one of the Virginia Tech groups that was at CLI&amp;nbsp;so we waited for him. By the time I got back from dinner it had begun to rain in a biblical manner. Soaked from head to toe, carrying a very competent but still underperforming umbrella, I decided that waiting until morning would be just as suitable since it isn't a long trip and we would arrive there pretty late anyway.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a night on the couch at CLI, my third in four weeks, I woke and we headed out to the bus station. We bought tickets no problem and got to Yang Shou.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our immediate thought was "first things first, time for some western breakfast." We stopped in a caf&amp;eacute;, I had "英式早餐" (English style breakfast) which apparently means eggs, bacon, a small French bagett, a cup of Lipton tea with one sugar, and mango juice. It was satisfying. At the time it was raining. Wilson, as I would point later, in an almost&amp;nbsp;soothsayingly correct way said "hey the rain is letting up, if we are going to go we should go now." Then it didn't rain for like two hours.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next part of our journey was to venture out of the city to see a mountain that has a cresent moon shape hole in the top. To get there we rented bikes. The ride was enormously&amp;nbsp;relaxing. &amp;nbsp;Nothing beats whizzing&amp;nbsp;by fellow tourists and other motor vehicles by your own power. After about a 7km ride we reached what we thought was the ticket office. Immediately upon getting to the area we had people yelling "Hello!", "You want to climb mountain. I take you there 5 yuan." We were skeptical, and fully capable of doing it ourselves. So on we continued. We kept going up the hill until we saw a group of about 30 Chinese tourists taking pictures of the same thing pointing the opposite direction we were going. I looked at what they were looking at, off in the near distance there was the mountain in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So off we went back towards the mountain. We got up to the ticket office another kilometer up the road and people were still trying to "help us get in" for a charge. What was really happening was they were trying to guide us 12 feet to the ticket office and buy a ticket for us for a 5 yuan&amp;nbsp;surcharge. Nope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We climbed the mountain. It was beautiful. See photos when I post them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back down to town we went. We got soaked in the rain, yes it basically rained for the remainder of the day. We all went and bought a change of cloths and change into them at the restaurant at which we ate dinner. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then proceeded to walk around a bit, not really knowing what to do with ourselves. It was a little to early to go to a bar, but we had pretty well done everything else that we wanted to do that day. After a bit we looked for a rooftop bar, they are common in Yang Shou. We ended up, completely by chance, at one that one of the CLI&amp;nbsp;staff members had recommended. We ended up playing poker with the Jane of Monkey Jane's the hostel and bar at which we were frequenting. She was not very good at poker. At 8:30 we left to head back to Guilin. Getting a cab is not exactly easy in Yang Shou, and in the rain it is even more discouraging. Also, they are not marked as cabs, they are just these little mini-van type cars driving around picking people up. When we hailed one successfully we told the driver we were going to Guilin, which is what Monkey Jane instructed us to tell the cab driver and they would take us to the bus station. Well the next words out of the guys mouth were 300 yuan (or about 50 USD). All of us looked at each other and said, "uhhhhhh&amp;nbsp;what?" We were more expecting 20 yuan&amp;nbsp;at maximum. We then explained a bit further, because our Chinese is more than capable to communicate such a thought. He laughed and said get in 20 Yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the day I said that I would be really upset if I left one of my bags behind, and almost did, because in it was one of my favorite shirts and a water bottle that I have accidentally almost left behind like 10 times in different places. Well, I ended up leaving it in the cab. When we sat down on the bus and were waiting to buy our tickets and depart someone walked up to me and said, "is this bag yours?" I didn't know what was happening at first. However, I came to and it was the cab driver. He brought me the bag in question. I had left it in the cab. So China decided to cut me some slack that day&amp;mdash;not so merciless&amp;nbsp;after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I got back to my homestay&amp;nbsp;fairly late. I poked my head into the living room, where the homestay&amp;nbsp;Dad (to whom I have not been introduced) was playing Mahjong with his friends. I said hello and promptly went to my room and proceeded to sleep until noon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I proceeded to hang out in my room and work on the blundering mess that is this website for most of the day, and wait for my homestay&amp;nbsp;mom to come grab me for the aforementioned 出去玩. However she never came to get me. We never went to do her plans. It wasn't until I went to ask her what was for dinner later in the evening that she even knew I was home. She just assumed I didn't come home and obviously didn't communicate with any other family members, who had all seen me since my arrival. She is a terrible communicator. So basically she ruined my last weekend in a way because I could have been in Yang Shou&amp;nbsp;a whole day more, Oh well; what can you do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why I feel on top of the world, and therefore China, is that none of the things recently that have happened are effecting me. Weird homestay problems, laughable. Language skills have rapidly improved and I am feeling nearing&amp;nbsp;proficient&amp;nbsp;at times. But more than anything I vanquished&amp;nbsp;the bane of my Guilin&amp;nbsp;existence.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I feared since it was late they would have locked me out. It has been raining, and given last weeks door situation explaination that I recieved I assumed, correctly that I had been locked out. (Side note my phone I had left in the car the day before so I was phoneless.) The door was tied shut. My normal reaction to a situation like this is anger and self blame. This time I immediately said to myself, "to hell with any amount of politeness, I am untying this door." and I did. I felt so victorious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sit in my room quite proud of myself and report to you my upbeat outlook on the weekend. This weekend China 0 - Jackson 1. Tune in for the rematch that happens daily.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. It was pointed out to me that there has been a lack of proper revisions on this blog for grammar and general sense making. I do apologize and will be giving it a once over&amp;nbsp;when time permits, but learning Chinese completely destroys one's ability to write proper English.&amp;nbsp;不好意思。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>