<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>two hours of really unrestful sleep, skittles and Daft Punk's "Human After All"</title>
  <slug>two-hours-of-really-unrestful-sleep-skittles-and-daft-punks-human-after-all</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-07-05 08:43:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Nine hours into a hardseater train ride from Inner Mongolia to Beijing. &lt;br /&gt;My only real thought right now is, "Are we there yet?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently running on two hours of really unrestful sleep, skittles and Daft Punk's "Human After All" album&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This train ride has certainly been the most interesting. The conversation that I had with the people that were sitting with me last night was pretty interesting. The occasional other person walked over and joined the WaiGuo conversation. As opposed to previous experiences, the older gentleman actually wanted to talk about things that weren't just pleasantries. He wanted to talk about my opinion of Japanese people. He was definitely not a fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few hours everyone made attempts to go to sleep or got off of the train. All that was left of the original chatting group was me and the college Junior from Hainan. He has a long trip ahead of him. On this train there are two sides with groups of two rows that face each other, one has three seats, the other has two. We had two seats each. They were just long enough to make you try to lie down, but not long enough to be remotely comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hainan guy was actually my savior for the night. He had a portable phone charger. The one I just bought apparently didn't hold its charge. He let me use his charger and charge my phone allowing me to continue listening to my music on my headphones that are down a plastic earbud thingy (technical term). I am a bit of a mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people I feel the most for though are those who are bought 无座 tickets. What that means is no seat, i.e. standing room only. Some people seem to be nice enough to rotate a bit with the standing room only people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning at around 7 o'clock or so we made a stop in some where maybe three hours out of Beijing. What proceeded seemed almost unprecedented. The train car I was on, which was about maybe a third filled, became filled and filled predominantly with young women. I am now convinced that this place must be the is the Loyola Chicago of China. 2/3 girls and you'll never see a guy for the forest of women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girls that sat down with me after the bombardment of estrogen into the train car have not seemed to interested in me, so I have made no attempts at conversation with me. I always wonder if they think I can't speak Chinese or I just don't want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girl currently sitting next to me is eating sunflower seeds like she is getting paid 10 Yuan a seed. If this is the case I think she has made somewhere in the vicinity of 150,000 Yuan in the last hour or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently looking at a river or some sort. My Chinese geography is not great, but I am unaware of any rivers that are as close to Beijing as I would hope that I currently am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be more than making up for the fact that this eleven hour train ride only cost around $12 by splurging on western goodies at Jenny Lou's grocery store.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>