<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Day 7 - Happy 'Murica Day</title>
  <slug>day-7---happy-murica-day</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-07-04 23:59:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;I couldn't feel farther from my mother land of the USA on our most sacred drinking festival. I am in a car, returning from the grasslands of Inner Mongolia, sandwiched between two Italians with a brit in the front seat and a native Mongolian driving the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After yesterday's wonderful sunset, many of us decided that we would get up to see the sunrise as well. After my less than stellar night of sleep, I could not be bothered to get out of bed for any other reasons than food, and leaving for somewhere warm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we were woken up for food I, of course, had my normal reaction to the thought of putting Chinese breakfast in my body---skepticism. However, I was pleasantly surprised by what was served. We had some sort of bread, and milk tea with a sort of pellet sized seed in it. The milk tea and seeds tasted enough like cereal and milk to qualify as my "American meal for the day." However, my real meal is going to be Homeplate BBQ in Beijing (as well as the three to four bagels I am going to consume in quick succession in Sanlitun).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next on the agenda was to head back to Hohhot to switch drivers and send Jim back to the hostel. On the way we stopped for a bathroom break. The theme song to my bathroom break was apparently an instrumental rendition of "My Heart Will Go On" from the movie Titanic. One, it is funny what songs you will hear in the middle of nowhere in China. Two, it is not the first time that song has come on in an out of place location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a two and a half hour drive we arrived in outer Hohhot. We actually didn't switch drivers yet, but we added an English speaking tour guide. Her English name was Dimples, which is just a fantastic English nickname. The vast majority of the trip I was doing some rudimentary translation between Simone and Matteo, and Dimples. Being the translator in the room is not a role to which I am accustomed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After another drive of about two hours we arrived to the dessert. The highlights of the dessert were that we played sand soccer and the drive through the dunes to reach the camel riding spot and that I bought a hat before we entered the dessert and didn&amp;rsquo;t burn my face to the point that I would have wished for death, which was a potential outcome of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night before I had been told by a fellow traveler at the hostel that camel ridding was a horrifying experience. He and his wife are also bloggers so her is a link about their experience &amp;lt;Link HERE&amp;gt; (Worth Reading). Long story short is that apparently riding a one hump camel is hard on your manhood. Well thankfully riding on a two camel horse is not a similar situation. It was a physically comfortable experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the experience was uncomfortable in a different regard, which has caused me to decide that I will never ride a camel again by my own choice. The people running the place ran the treated the camels in a inhumane manor. I will not describe what was going on, it wasn't the worst thing I could imagine, but it was enough to decide that I will not be creating any more demand for touristy torture camps. It was also frustrating to watch the Chinese tourists, unburdened by any shred of guilt, snap pictures and have a great time at the expense of a bunch of innocent animals. I would have rather just walked through the dunes on my own two feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On to a more light subject:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ride back to Hohhot was much more of the same, teaching a little bit of English to my new pupils, speaking a bit of Chinese with the driver and dimples. After we arrived back to the guest house all the guests started to accumulate in the&amp;nbsp; living room area. For several hours we sat half watching "The adventures of Shark Boy and Lava Girl" and "Wild Wild West" with Will Smith and half swapping stories of our travels and the like. You can learn more about the world sitting in a room such as that than from any book than I can imagine. Such a diverse group of Lao Wai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that was dinner with people from the hostel. I went and had "chuan" (or in 北京话 chuar) for the first time since studying abroad in Beijing. I don't know why I didn't get any while I was in Guilin. (For those of you who don't know what that is, it is Chinese kebabs.) After that it was time to prepare my stuff and my soul for the overnight hard-seater train to Beijing. The Italians and I got to the train station none too early. They had already almost finished boarding everyone when we got through security. I would have been quite alright if we had not had to get on that train. I was expecting the worst.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>