<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Airport, Plane, Vroom, High Altitude Vroom, Screeech, Airport, Bus, Gai Fan (Changsha to Lanzhou)</title>
  <slug>airport-plane-vroom-high-altitude-vroom-screeech-airport-bus-gai-fan-changsha-to-lanzhou</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-06-30 23:59:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;The lady next to me on the plane chatted with me quite a bit and helped me find the bust to the Lanzhou city center. Very helpful. Another person willing to help just because I was another human being. Hopefully this is the theme of the entire trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was greeted to the north of China with just a wonderful sign when I walked around the corner. A little mom and pop 盖饭 (things on top of rice with a sauce)resturant. Enough of the crap that I was eating in the south, good food would abound for the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hopped in the second cab that stopped for me, the first cabbie didn't know where I was trying to go, or at least he couldn't read the traditional characters that in which my hotel confirmation was written. I was accidentally on the Hong Kong site when I booked the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got there and immediately confirmed my suspicion that I had booked a way too nice hotel. $50 apparently goes a long way in a hotel. I knew this fact, but didn't really think about it when I booked it in a rush the night before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately got out of the hotel and went out into the park nearby to take pictures. (The theme for the rest of the day.) The park was a sort of mountain with lots of traditional buildings. I am not exactly sure what they are called, see my pictures and you will know exactly what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After walking down from taking pictures I noticed a building that seemed to be a restaurant in the lower part of the park. I walked in and asked if I could be seated. I must have a looked confused because the lady asked what I wanted. I then, because I was then flustered and thought I was not supposed to be there, asked if it was a restaurant. She then asked me if I wanted to eat food. I said I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of thing seems to happen a lot. I must have a confused or stupid face, because people are constantly thinking that I am confused or stupid. That or maybe I am white. 没办法.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a solid 20 minutes trying to make sense of their menu and finding something that wasn't too expensive to eat I ordered, sat down, journaled, ate and left. When I got to the exit of the park it seemed that I was locked in the park. I stood for about thirty seconds considering what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point I continued to the other side of the river via a walking bride taking even more pictures as I went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After walking about an hour or so I decided to turn back. I was walking back along the river and intended to go straight back to my swanky hotel, however, I saw a side street that looked interesting enough to walk down. So I did. I was rewarded for my willingness to not lazily go back to the hotel with a wonderful little caf&amp;eacute;. It really felt like I had walked into a hip little caf&amp;eacute; in a trendy area in Chicago, like Roger's Park or something like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up ordering an absolutely lovely up of warm milk tea and getting and just relaxing. Once I was seated the were playing Frank Sinatra in the background. Half way around the world, in a pretty far out the way city, you can still feel comfortable, you can still feel like you are supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very quickly after sitting down the manager came over and asked if he could take a picture with me on his little polaroid camera. I was of course obliging. For the most part everyone left me alone the rest of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After milking my tea for about an hour I set out for the hotel and went to sleep. Or at least I thought sleep. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think about it but the milk tea had quite a lot of caffeine and sugar. So sleep was not exactly the easiest thing to achieve.&amp;nbsp; My plan for tomorrow is to get up and see the sunrise on top of the hill and get out onto the river somehow.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>