<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>A report on the camping trip</title>
  <slug>a-report-on-the-camping-trip</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-06-06 23:34:31</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Ya, it's been like a week since I have posted on here, I would say I have been to busy, but I would more say that I have been to lazy to write anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said it was a busy, weird fun weekend and week. Ok so, the quick version of the camping trip I went on: On Saturday morning my host mom asked me if I wanted to go, and I was only half positive that she was asking me if I wanted to go and not just telling me that they were going.&amp;nbsp;So, Sunday morning&amp;nbsp;I got prepared and was hanging around the house waiting for instructions. Eventually we left, but I waited around nervously for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We piled in the car&amp;nbsp;with my host Mom's "friends." These guys were&amp;nbsp;both about my age so I&amp;nbsp;didn't quite understand how they would have been acquainted. I never asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a 3 hour trip, we stopped at a rest area. This is when I first saw the magnitude of the group we were traveling with. It was about five cars full of people. Not a small camping group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the stop we then had about an hour trip up the mountain on what I can only describe as&amp;nbsp;treacherous and uncomfortable roads. The funniest, but also most&amp;nbsp;nerve-racking, thing was when we were about half way up there was a back hoe blocking the road. On closer inspection, what it was doing was clearing a rock slide. EEEEKK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that bit of scary, we made it to the campsite. It was quite beautiful. Please refer to pictures I am not going to describe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip was mildly fun, not really. The problem was that I was on a mountain with a bunch of people whose language I barely speak, who I also don't know&amp;mdash;and then&amp;mdash;they were speaking a dialect that I don't understand a word of. So I wouldn't say that I was able to engage in too much conversation, which was the reason I thought going on the trip would really be worth while. So basically I just walked around the camp site aimlessly, taking some photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening the force feed me an unhealthy amount of food. Way.&amp;nbsp;Too. Much. Food.&amp;nbsp;I'm full&amp;nbsp;apparently wasn't a good enough, although true, excuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also discovered on the trip that my&amp;nbsp;illness, that I thought was a sinus infection or an ear&amp;nbsp;infection was actually just a cold. So&amp;nbsp;that was good, but it made me a bit uncomfortable. I think the vast majority of any time someone said something to me on the trip was: are you sick or would you like to eat some of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's all I've got to say about that.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>