<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>A really fun weekend in Long Shen 龙胜</title>
  <slug>a-really-fun-weekend-in-long-shen-龙胜</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-06-09 01:14:26</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;So weekend number two: once again I found myself in the mountains. It could not be more different (in terms of being in china). I went from hanging out with a bunch of locals that I didn't know, whose language I didn't speak, to hanging out with all English speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Here's the break-down of people, and again it was a great bunch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Jake: American University rising Junior studying International Relations. Second time in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Emma from England: Spent the last year studying at a university in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Wilson: Computer Science graduate from Virginia Tech, going to work for Amazon in Seattle next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Devon: Smiley little rising high school Junior. No more explanation necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Jeffrey: His Chinese name is Harry Potter. He has been in Guilin for several months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Ice and Nancy: CLI staff members leading the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Myself: Jackson Hayes, the guy with the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;The weekend began with Friday night maybe 40 or so people from CLI going to KTV. That was a sight to behold. I don't think I will be going to go sing karaoke any time in the near future. It is just proof that I can't sing that I don't need. People's usual line is, "I can't do karaoke without being drunk." (Smirk)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;We met at about 7:30 at CLI to hop on a 10 person car-bus to head out to Long Shen. It was about a two hour ride, I took a few photos and we chit the chat with my fellow travelers. We got to the base of Long Shen, and we were told, this bus can't go any farther we have to change buses. This was a tad disconcerting because, if this small bus can't make it up the hills we are going on, what are we getting ourselves into. However, this was not the case. We had to pass through a ticket gate, and then get on a bigger bus that was owned by whoever ran the tourism office around Long Shen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US" style="font-family: Calibri;"&gt;We got up to the area where the hotel was and it was immediately clear that it was a holiday at a popular Chinese tourist spot. There were people everywhere. (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="zh-CN" style="font-family: SimSun;"&gt;人山人海&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US" style="font-family: Calibri;"&gt;). After dropping our stuff at the hotel we went and grabbed lunch at a resturant called "&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="zh-CN" style="font-family: SimSun;"&gt;没有&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US" style="font-family: Calibri;"&gt;" which means don't have. Their sign said something to the effect of : We &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="zh-CN" style="font-family: SimSun;"&gt;没有：&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US" style="font-family: Calibri;"&gt;bad food, bad service, cold food, warm beer, etc. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US" style="font-family: Calibri;"&gt;What we found from the two meals that we ate there was that they indeed had bad service, and they did not have the hamburgers for which we specifically returned to eat for dinner. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="zh-CN" style="font-family: SimSun;"&gt;这是中国&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US" style="font-family: Calibri;"&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Most of the day we spent walking up and down the trails in the rice terraces. I was really hard to appreciate the beauty of this thousands of years old scenic treasure: first, there were people everywhere (I was however just as pleased to take photos of them) and second I have already seen rice terraces before, and the ones in the Hani village were much more memorable because they were not part of a tourist trap.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;They have a very interesting tradition in Long Shen during the rice planting festival that was going this weekend. That tradition is that they gather people in the terraces and throw out chickens into the terrace. The instructions on our guide sheet said (in fantastically broken English that I can't remember specifically) if a person catches a chicken, it is their chicken. Basically someone threw the chicken, people chased the chickens, someone grabbed the chicken, then the chickens neck was snapped. Dinner? Why? Because China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;The night time activity was very unsurprising for me. It was a performance of traditional song and dance of the ethnic group that was native to that area. I don't remember the name. They did a pretty cool dance with the large bamboo shoot sticks though. The problem was that the area that they were performing was swarming with people, so you couldn't see anything. It's those kind of moments when I really appreciate how unique an experience the Yunnan excursion with TBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;What was quite funny about the swarms of tourists was, when everyone was waiting around for the villagers to come into the area and start the performance everything was mostly calm. People staked out their spots, and some serious photogramatures set up their tripods in one area. As soon as the villagers entered the area everything descended into anarchy. Everyone made a tight circle around the performers and blocked out the people with the tripods. They were not in the least bit pleased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;After the performance there was a fireworks show over the rice terraces. Beautiful. Unfortunately I spent most of my time behind the lens of my camera so I didn't appreciate it as much as I should have. More on this in a upcoming post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;After the fireworks we met up with another group of CLI people from Virginia Tech at a caf&amp;eacute;-bar. The owner was an interesting person, he spoke some very excited-welcoming-yet-very-broken English. The Virginia Tech leader recommended that we try the apple pie which he had tried the last time he had visited Long Shen. My rating of the apple pie: it was over cooked, the apples slices looked more like some kind of meat somehow, it tasted pretty much like apple pie. It gets a C+, when applying the curve for western food in China-- A-.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;The next morning we had Chinese breakfast in the small lobby of the hotel where we had stayed. This is an important note for the next part of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;We then proceeded to get on a bus to go to the next mountain in the Long Shen area. The bus ride was very reminiscent of the bus rides through Yunnan with TBC. The same kind of buses, the same kind of crazy Formula One driving tactics on roads with rock slides sitting on the road and 100 ft. cliffs on the outside of the road. I was very car sick. Curse you Chinese breakfast and your stomach unsettling nonsense. I would estimate that I could have survived about twenty-five more minutes without having breakfast resurfacing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;Quick side note: as I am sitting here writing I hear the preschoolers next door. They sound as though they have made their first kill of the morning and are fighting over the carcass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;The mountain on the second day was wonderful for two reasons. First, there were far less people there. Second, there was a gondola to the top of the mountain. Many wonderful pictures taken from the cable car, from the top of one of the mountains and while walking down the mountain in the terrace paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;From that point we walked back to the central bus point, hoped on a bus, then met our bus driver and his lady friend that was with him. (He picked her up on the way to Long Shen in Guilin and dropped her off at a Hotel before we arrived back to CLI, you draw your own conclusion on what was going on with that.) We had the driver drop us of at McDonalds. End of cultural experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;P.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: Calibri;"&gt;More news from the preschool. They were chanting along to some song about cookies or crackers (the word is basically the same in Chinese) when all of the sudden Gangam style came on. The started screaming like a bunch of little girls when Justin Beiber walks onto a stage. It was an incredible moment. HEEYYY SEXY LADY. Who plays that for children?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>