<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>A Mistake one Needs to Make?</title>
  <slug>a-mistake-one-needs-to-make</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-09-14 19:45:47</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-05 22:29:36</lastModified>
  <excerpt></excerpt>
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Lately I have been interested in the a certain thought process that occurs to people from time to time when they face a decision. This thought process can be titled "A mistake I need to make." &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First off this phrase is interesting, because it almost cannot exist in isolation. However often one might say it to oneself, the phrase is somehow in response to something. This is because if one thinks this decision they are about to make was actually a mistake, and they wouldn't actually make that decision. What the phrase really says is that there is someone or something that exists either outside of the person or in the minority of "the senate of one's mind" (a phrase made up) and the decision maker does not agree. The right course of action is this mistake.    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In thinking over this phrase over the last few weeks, my initial response was that there is no such thing as a "mistake I need to make" or a mistake that is a correct course of action. Like I said previously, a mistake is a mistake whether or not we think it is a mistake. My reasoning behind this was that inherently there are effects that come from any decision a person makes. Those effects can either be good or bad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However this morning an analogy came into my head that seems to be fitting that contradicts my previous thought. This analogy is the concept of a gambit in board games such as Chess.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A gambit is when one player creates a scenario that gives his or her opponent an initial advantage but it later turns out that when played correctly that the situation actually turns back in the favor of the player giving away the initial advantage. For example in the "Kings gambit, white moves two pawns forward in its first two moves offering a free pawn to be taken by black. However, this black pawn that takes the white pawn is very vulnerable and will probably be lost later in the game. So when offered a gambit a player has two choices, to accept the gambit or decline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The analogy of the gambit declined is the more telling in terms of real life "correct mistakes" In most scenarios in life when one makes the right choice, the one that most people, ethical and moral guidelines, and logic would agree with usually end up rewarding the person who makes that choice. This unfortunately does not encompass every scenario that one could come across. It is possible that there be a scenario that making a mistake will actually lead to a better outcome in life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is the example I will give. Imagine A college freshman, in the middle of his or her first semester, we will call this student Jordan (a nice gender neutral name). Jordan is deciding whether or not to skip his or her 8:00 am Friday Philosophy 101 class. Jordan knows he or she should go to class but he or she decides not to go. It turns out that on that given Friday, there was not a pop quiz as you think example might give, but there is an additional reading that is being added to the quiz was already scheduled for Monday that the Jordan knew about from the syllabus. Jordan arrives on Monday for class and the aforementioned quiz. However, Jordan does poorly on the quiz. This is the natural result that one would expect from the mistake of missing a class and missing that information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However life is much more complex than one act causing one effect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After class this poor freshman walks up to the tenured Philosophy professor to speak his or her mind about the quiz being on material that was not in the syllabus. The Professor of course in a quick and decisive way puts the student in his or her place saying, "you were unprepared for this quiz because you failed to show up for class on Friday where I informed everyone that the quiz material was to include the new and enlightening reading that I added for the betterment of your education."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jordan then walks back to his or her dorm with his or her tail between his or her legs thinking, "Wow, confronting him was a bad idea I was totally in the wrong there." The lesson learned was not that skipping classes was bad, because the student knew that already, what they learned was not to try to bring up perceived injustices that have been inflicted on the someone when not all the facts are known.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward six years in the now graduated college student's life. They are at their first job that they have been working at for 11 months. Jordan has been forced to work 75 hour weeks even though when he or she was hired they were assured the company had a great work life balance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We now must imagine two Jordans. Jordan gambit acceptor went to class and never learned the lesson. Jordan the gambit decliner made the mistake and learned the lesson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jordan gambit decliner then decides to confront his or her boss saying, "I can't put up with these long hours anymore, this is not what I signed up for, this is not what I was told my life would be like when I started." It is not wrong to speak up when you feel you are being wronged. However, unbeknownst to Jordan, Jordan's employer was close to going bankrupt, and the company was trying to get ahead of its current work ahead of time in hopes that they could find more revenue and opportunities after getting ahead. However, the board of directors has advised all senior managers to start cutting costs and letting go nonessential staff where possible, but not to give details to the company at large that the company is in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The boss's obvious response to Jordan's confrontation is, "well if that is the way you feel, and you aren't as committed to the company as everyone else is, you can pack up your desk and get out straight away. You're fired."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now take our other Jordan, he or she is struggling with the same issue of being overworked and underappreciated. However, when this Jordan confronts his or her boss, this Jordan asks "we seem to be all hands on deck lately, is there any reason for it?" This Jordan wants more information, not to confront. This Jordan now continues to have job, whereas the other Jordan is living at home with his or her parents in the suburbs, didn't meet the person of his or her dreams and missed his or her shot at being a rock start because they got fired and weren't in the right place at the right time. (Yes I know that escalated quickly.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is worse about this whole idea is that all one can actually do is try not to make mistakes. (Although obviously you must learn from all your mistakes.) This is because unlike Chess, you cannot know which decisions are the gambits and which ones are just plain mistakes. Life is too complicated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So in summary, we should not say this is a "mistake I need to make," there is no way one can know. Unfortunately the situation is much more theoretical, it is that you could make all the "right" decisions and still end up not as far as you could have gotten. Making the right decisions is the safe road and has proved statistically to be the safe path. Whereas making mistakes takes you to the statistical extremes. God, fate, whatever it is that is or isn’t out there seems to have stacked the deck in certain circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The point is this though, in real life choosing a mistake is a delusion. It is a selfish belief that one can get the short term benefits of a mistake and the long term benefits of a good decision. So I give you the same advice I gave to a friend the other day: "Make good decisions, and you are the judge of good," because you can't know what the outcome of your actions will be but things done in earnest for good usually create more good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Also if you found it aggravating that I wrote he or she, his or her everywhere that was the point as well. A apologetic grammatical form intended to make everyone happy that makes everyone unhappy. Life.]&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories>
    <category>Ramblings</category>
  </categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>