<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>LanZhou or "Here Be Dragons:</title>
  <slug>lanzhou-or-here-be-dragons</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-07-03 23:59:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;This morning I got up, not early enough to see the sunrise on the mountain as planned, to head into the white pagoda park. I went back through to a few places that I had been in the lower part of the park to retake some pictures that needed to be taken with day light. I made my way up the mountain (hill) quickly. After about 30 minutes of stairs and photographs I got to the pagoda area. I went around the right side which seemed to be the entrance, nope. I went around the left, nope. Apparently the temple area was undergoing some sort of construction project, typical. The next thing on the list was to walk over to the other part of the park which had a Confucian temple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way there were some great views of the city and a couple of very auspicious dogs that lived up there. I passed by the gondola that went from the hill to downtown. It appeared to me as though it hadn&amp;rsquo;t been used in years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got to the Confucian temple, it was pretty dead. The ticket stand lady was sitting outside the front of the building she was supposed to be manning. After hesitantly, not knowing if I needed to buy a ticket or not, waiting by side of the entrance I walked over and asked her if I needed to buy a ticket. She said something unintelligible to me in Chinese, and presumably because I looked confused or grunting something to the effect she said&amp;nbsp; "mian fei" which means free. I then began walking toward the entry way to the temple following her. She turned around and something else mostly unintelligible, and followed it with "hu zhao?" which means passport. Of course I didn&amp;rsquo;t have my passport, who carries their passport in a park. Every traveler who isn't a complete moron keeps their passport in the safest place available to them.&amp;nbsp; For me of course that was my locked, four star hotel room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So advice to anyone planning on visiting a Chinese tourist attraction: if it is free you need your passport. So basically always carry your passport when you are being touristy. Alternatively I also think this is not a wise idea because losing a passport in China sounds like the biggest annoyance that could befall a traveler. So head my advice and continue not knowing what you should do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have often said that if it were a viable option I would staple my passport to my arm so that losing it would not be an option. First that wouldn't be very stylish and second breaking the barrier that your provides with a staple would allow far too much China to get into your body, and no one wants that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of going in I took a few pictures from outside the gate and then proceeded to the other side of the temple to go down the hill. (Yes it is a mountain on the way up and a hill on the way down, that is how it works.) On the other side more of the temple was visible and there was a great view of the city and a fair amount of people going about their morning rituals. A few people were playing badminton. I sat at the top of the hill, wrote in my journal, and just took in the scene. In my travels, especially while I have been traveling alone, I move, move, move. I don't often enough just sit, relax and take in what is around me or use this time as what it actually is, a vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having some other tourists snap a photo of me, and snapping a photo of one of them who was very eager for me to take his picture, I made my way down the hill. When I reached the bottom I made my way down to the walking bridge to get across the street and go get on a boat to see some of the river. When I looked back up the mountain I noticed that there were gondolas coming down from the mountain. I guess looks can be deceiving. Also, it was just not my day as far as my plans went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From then on the day went smoothly. Got on a boat (paid two people's price to go immediately and by myself on a little boat on the river). Went to the provincial museum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend Wilson from CLI, every time I mention going to one of the north or north west provinces in China he always mentions the phrase "here be dragons." It is kind of true, this part of the map basically says, ya there are cities here but there is nothing out here. Just as in olden times when the edges of the map just had pictures of dragons. We don't know what is here and we don't want to know. Well if found out what it is that is here and indeed there are dragons. Well dinosaur fossils but close enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these dinosaurs is hilariously called the Sinosaurus 中国龙. (Yes that is the name.) When I picture the word Sinosaurus I think of a cluster of 80 year old Chinese men and women dancing in the park. (Which is a fairly comon sight.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Train station -&amp;gt; Overnight train -&amp;gt; 呼和浩特（huhehaote or Hohhot).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>