<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>A Confused and Slow Assault of the Great Wall</title>
  <slug>a-confused-and-slow-assault-of-the-great-wall</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-07-06 23:30:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Wilson and I got a somewhat slower start than we wanted. First off we went to Tavin's, a ten minute walk, and it was closed. Rough start to the morning. So we headed back to the hostel and ate breakfast there. Eventually we got on our way. After a stop at the ATM which was on the way we arrived at the Dongzhimen bus station. Our first blunder in a series of blunders was to wait in line for the regular bus instead of the express bus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually a little old lady that was probably wanting to sell us a trip somewhere asked us where we were going. We told her, and she said we were about to get on the wrong train. She probably saved us two hours of extra travel if we had stayed on this bus. I was flustered and relayed to Wilson what she had told me, he wasn't standing right next to me when she told me, and started to walk away. The lady then barked at me 不谢谢我？Are you not going to thank me? In her defense I should have thanked her, in my defense I had already thanked her once, or at least in my head I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So sometimes when people help you can walk away feeling less good than you did before. This is not the first time I have experienced the phenomenon on this trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the welcome but harsh help from the old lady we made our way over to the correct bus line. We did not have exact change so a very enterprising man standing by the line sold us a water bottle for 3 kuai to make change for us. This is the theme of the next hour or so of the trip, enterprising people making a living off of the needs of tourists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once on the bus wearing a bus company shirt asked us where we were going. We told him and he walked on. On the bus Wilson and I chatted and tried to make sense of the directions I pulled off of the internet. Suddenly the man from before told us that our stop was approaching, without thinking we got off. As I was getting off I was pretty sure that we were one stop short of where we were going. The man in the official looking shirt also got off of the bus with us. The bus pulled away and I immediately knew what had happened. He walked over and asked if he wanted to pay him to take us where we wanted to go. Oh I was livid. I don't get angry very easily, but I do not like it when someone tries to blatantly take advantage of me. Both Wilson and I speak enough Chinese that we shouldn't be the normal target of this sort of trickery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly what I said to him at first but, what I was thinking included plenty of words I try to avoid using on the internet or around my grandmother. I then tried to ignore his persistent questioning. I was trying to figure out how far from the stop we wanted to get off of was from where we were. I determined that we were one stop away from where we were had intended to go. We asked one of the other guys standing around where we should go and he could tell we were pissed at this guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitting here writing this days later I am can still feel how upset I was in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other guy explained that we not close to where we were going, we still had an hour drive to the Jiankou part of the wall and the cab driver would have to wait for us while we went to the wall. So finally after the driver explained the same thing we got in his 面包车. We drove for the hour or so, still entirely skeptical of the whole situation, and who knows maybe never had any intention of taking us anywhere we wanted to go. There was a whole range of motives he could haveand I would have believed any of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilson made a great point at one point during the day about the situation, "that guy sniped us from the moment we stepped in line at the bus station." It was true, he was clever, he was ready and he knew what he was on about, and in the end he got our money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once he dropped us off everything seemed more or less how we expected. We were skeptical that we were in the right place up until we bumped into some people coming down the trail saying that we had about forty minutes more before we would reach the wall. At that point we felt a little bit more relaxed, other than the fact that there was a bee that followed us from basically the beginning of the trail all the way to the top of the mountain where the wall was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the experience I will let these two quotes and the photos associated speak for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The great thing about a wall is that you can't get lost, you can only go two directions." - Wilson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilson on pets: "They are soft cuddly creatures that don't hate you, which is generally a good thing"&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>