<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Why I Dislike the Ellipsis</title>
  <slug>why-i-dislike-the-ellipsis</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-08-30 15:25:46</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 03:17:15</lastModified>
  <excerpt></excerpt>
  <content>&lt;p&gt;I take it on precedent that one is allowed to dislike certain words, punctuation marks or other parts of language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just today learned today that C.S. Lewis disliked the word gentleman. It used to be a statement of fact about a man with a crest and owned land. Now the word is used to compliment someone on their behavior or chastise someone for behavior you deem poor. We already had words for such ideas, and by muddling the word gentleman with the new usage, the old usage lost almost all of its meaning without need of preference or explanation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My dear beloved Kurt Vonnegut described the semicolon as "they are transvestite hermaphrodite s that represent nothing. All they do is show you've been to college."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So today I will begin to describe my dislike for the ellipsis. Unfortunately I don't stand on a firm footing as the aforementioned men. Lewis speaks of a word that has lost its true meaning, which is a mean spirited thing to take away from a word since that is all it has at the end of the day. Vonnegut points out that if we had never saw another semicolon in out lives we would be no worse off than we are today. We could maybe even give children a week off of school over their grade school years instead of teaching the proper use of a semicolon. (As you may be able to tell, I too dislike the semicolon. (I, however, love using parenthesis))&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I dislike the ellipsis not because it serves no purpose but because I don't like what it's purpose is. The entomology of the word ellipsis is omission. Inherent in the usage of an ellipsis is to leave something out that was previously included.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In interest of brevity I will provide legitimate usages of the ellipsis then give my aggravating examples of those three little dots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The obvious first place to use an ellipsis is when quoting a long quote and only providing the most important parts supporting the claim you are making. This is obviously legitimate and enough to secure the ellipsis in the Oceania Newspeak guide to grammar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actually come to think of it this is the only standalone reason to use an ellipsis. Other than signalling a voice trailing off in a written dialogue. This then leads my long winded, sparsely read, unnecessary, and possibly wrong conclusion about the ellipsis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone has sent a text to someone that warranted the response of "Okay..." I find this response in written form utterly aggravating. It leaves too much to the imagination. Are you angry, do you want more information, are you surprised, are you confused. This response is as good as no response. The only information that you have given me is that you have read what I have sent you. I have am walking into a mine field if I choose to respond, and I choose to stand in a field Kamikaze tunneling groundhogs with C4 attached to their backs if I don't respond.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don't respond with "...," respond with something more useful to your reader. You owe it to them as a human being.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories>
    <category>Rants</category>
    <category> Stuff</category>
  </categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>