<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>(No, no, no, no) Beijing Take Two</title>
  <slug>no-no-no-no-beijing-take-two</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-07-05 23:59:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Now to recount my glorious return to Beijing. Simone, Matteo and I arrived to Beijing fairly early in the morning. I got checked into my room and helped the Italians on their way to what they wanted to see for the day. The moment I was able to I immediately headed for Tavin's bagels. I had chosen our hostel specifically because it was in Sanlitun and therefore close to Tavin's. Oh and it was heavenly. Let me tell you, when you haven&amp;rsquo;t had any sort of bread that can be reasonably called good in over a month I was over the moon in food joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once my stomach was filled with two bagels the next goal for the day was to meet up with Wilson and get in touch with the people that I was planning on seeing while in Beijing. I had quite a bit of trouble getting a hold of Wilson for some reason. I sat in the hostel or ran other errands while waiting for him to call me back. I don't honestly remember, I am writing this post a few days removed from Beijing and my journal is completely blank from this point up until the great wall some 30 hours later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually I got in contact with Wilson and we decided to meet where he was, which was Tiananmen square. He was visiting the Forbidden City and we had planned to go into the National Museum which is right across the street. We had a hilarious moment trying to find each other. He was in the square which you have to go through security to enter. So he walked up the set of stairs that would not take him out of the square, while I stood by the subway trying to tell him where I was on the phone. As we described where we were, of course in context to the giant picture of Mao that is on the entrance to the Forbidden City. Eventually we realized that we were on the opposite side of the main street, and after some I see you I am waving my arms do you see me were mutually found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was then determined that I should go through security so that we could go to see Mao's moseleum which I had yet to see. After waiting in a sweaty underground line of at least 1000 Chinese tourists I made it through security. We resurfaced only to find out that the moseleum was closed. To get anything in China worthwhile you must put in effort. However, sometimes you put in some amount of effort or a lot of effort and you have little or nothing to show for it. This was one of those times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So knowing that I wasn't getting in to the moselum I took a few photos of Tiananmen and we moved across the street to the museum. As we entered the museum we filled into line with all of the other tourists (all Chinese, which is an important comment for once even though I am constently making it clear that is what I mean). We made it to the ticket distribution area after about five minutes only to realize that it was not the proper line for us to be in, and we though we might not have even needed a to be in any line other than for the front door. There were signs that we thought indicated we only needed a passport. Wrong.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked over to the front door and tried to show our passports. The security guard put up his hand shook in front of us and said "no, no, no, no. It's just, it's justssss" and pointed at another ticket area. We went there, showed our passports, which were looked at only to verify that they looked like passports and not if they were ours or genuine and we were handed our tickets.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that bit of unnecessary bureaucracy we were in the museum. To be frank, for me museums can be quite boring. Yes things are old, I appreciate how old they are and that they are amazing treasures we must cherish in our society, but the problem with a museum is that when you are drowning in relics they begin to blur together. There will be almost nothing from the national museum that will stick out in my head other than the sleep deprived nonsense jokes that were coming out of my mouth at the expense of these relics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing we found particularly funny was that every vase or jar we saw was labeled as wine vessel for a good 10 minutes. As we walked the got bigger and bigger until eventually we came to something that looked more like a bathtub than a vase. Luckily for us it was labeled as a water container, because if it had been a wine vessel both Wilson and I would have died laughing right on the floor there amongst the throngs of Chinese tourists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point after a few hours we decided to ascend some stairs and go to a specific exhibit&amp;nbsp;(it escapes me which one it was.) As we approached the top of the stairs I met eyes with one of the security gaurds. She seemed to pay me no mind or even shot me a slight smile which i uncharacteristic of security guards here. I began to walk past her and what did she do. Well apparently in security gaurd school lesson one is "No, no, no, no." In that lesson you are taught how to deal with a foreigner&amp;nbsp;trying to go somewhere where they should not be as it is going to be a regular chore with which one will have to do. "No, no, no, no" became Wilson and my montra for the remainder of our weekend together. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recounting of details is getting tiresome so I will be brief on the next few bits. Dinner at Home Plate BBQ with Wilson and William, had some serious difficulty finding the place even though I had been there before (maybe having been there before was why we got lost, overconfidence). Drinks in Sanlitun with Cici and some current TBC summer students. Back to the hostel with plans to get up and go to the Great wall in the Morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will cut off my recounting of Beijing and separate the trip to the Wall into its own post because it has its own themes and its own flavor.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>