<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>A Trying First Week</title>
  <slug>a-trying-first-week</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-05-31 04:12:36</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;It has been quite a trying week to say the least. To start out with, my body has not really adjusted to well to being here. I am always tired, from the moment I wake up to the moment I accidentally fall asleep taking a study break at 8PM (Which happens every night basically.) I really don't know why I would be this tired. I mean, classes are long, like 20 hours a week long and then studying after class, but it doesn't fell like anything I a haven't done before.&amp;nbsp;That being said, getting essentially locked in a room with a native speaker for 4 hours a day is a fantastic way to learn a language.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next matter that was, I don't know, maybe one of the most terrifying emails I have ever received. It was from the Assistant&amp;nbsp;Dean of Arts and Sciences&amp;nbsp;at Loyola The paraphrased for humor jist&amp;nbsp;of it was this, "Hey so that degree you earned and you thought were just going to give you without a fuss, well, actually were not. It seems here that you are missing a Computer Science 300 level elective."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was of course news to me seeing how I had throughout college been meticulous about scheduling all of the classes that I needed to take, I kept in touch with my advisers, and did my graduation audits early and often. I emailed back saying "is there anything you missed, giving a few examples of things that might have been crossovers , I am pretty sure So what did I do? I sent a hail Mary pass of an email to undergraduate program coordinator&amp;nbsp;"Big RIG the ledgend Dr. Ronald Greenberg." He quickly responded saying that his records were in his office and he would get back to me in the morning. What did he do: this is what:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://boardgamequest.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/img_1688.jpg"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now before the conclusion of that saga, what happened to me shortly after reading this email. My home-stay brother, who with the grandma are the only people I have seen in the house since Tuesday night, comes in holding a bag of some sort of food. He asks if I have eaten. I say no even thought I had to be polite. He promptly drops a whole chicken in a bag on my desk and goes to get a chair. While getting the chair, in the weirdness of what was already rushing through my head plus this hilarious moment of cultural difference, I just silently burst out laughing. When God closes a door he apparently gives you a chicken.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we sat and ate chicken out of a bag and studied together, glove on one hand book in another.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward two days of silent worrying later (I didn't feel like talking to people a CLI about this because I don't really know them and if I talk about stuff like this I get really anxious and stressed), I get a very informal email back from him saying, "ya no big deal I see three classes that you took in the IS department that we sometimes consider adding to the list of accepted classes, and we have allowed people to take them as electives before, you are all good, I will let the College of Arts and Sciences people know." And then I prayed a silent prayer of thanks that email did not come back with the opposite sentiment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received&amp;nbsp;the aforementioned email in the early evening after dinner. I came back to my home-stay to drop off my back pack to go out with the CLIers&amp;nbsp;if my home-stay family didn't have anything going on. As I expected they weren't home. So I went out with the CLI&amp;nbsp;people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First we went to a local hostel to have a couple drinks. After that, with a girl named Anna from England that we met there, we went to a club. It is very fun being a white person in a Chinese club, you can do what eve you want and people think you look cool.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I headed towards home at about 1 AM. And I had brewed the perfect storm for something not so convenient&amp;nbsp;to happen. I forgot my phone and my keys to CLI&amp;nbsp;at my home stay, and I didn't tell anyone I was staying out late. When I got to my home stay as I should have expected they had locked the front door. Unfortunately not only do I not have a key, but they don't use a key. They lock the door with a piece&amp;nbsp;of string. So after 10 minutes of standing there like an idiot trying to figure out what to do I headed back to CLI&amp;nbsp;to sleep on the couch. Except I didn't have my key to there either, so I rang the door bell, and luckily one of my classmates heard it and let me in. Crisis mildly averted.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning I came back to my home-stay, kind of mad but mad at myself more than anything. I finally&amp;nbsp;saw my host sister. We laughed about the fact that we hadn't seen each other since Tuesday, It being Saturday mornin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then she invited me to go camping, we are leaving now. Got to go.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>