<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Jackson's Adventure Around China Day 1 Guilin to Changsha</title>
  <slug>jacksons-adventure-around-china-day-1-guilin-to-changsha</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-06-28 23:59:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Here is the tentative plan as of now for the first few days of the trip. &lt;br /&gt;June 28th Guilin -&amp;gt; Changsha &lt;br /&gt;June 29th Shaoshan day trip&lt;br /&gt;June 30th Changsha -&amp;gt; Lanzhou &lt;br /&gt;Jun 31st Lanzhou -&amp;gt; Huhehaote &lt;br /&gt;July 1st Huhehaote &lt;br /&gt;July 2nd -&amp;gt; 4th Inner Mongolia TBD&lt;br /&gt;July 5th - 6th Beijing&lt;br /&gt;July 7th Beijing -&amp;gt; TBD&lt;br /&gt;July 7th - 16th TBD&lt;br /&gt;As I walked out of the door to my home-stay to go to the train station my I got a message from my mom with a wonderful idea. "Steal the rope!" (The door locking rope that was the bane of my existence.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am ready for this adventure in almost every way I can think of. CLI has prepared me with an awesome level of Chinese language, maybe better than I had hoped when I arrived. I have basically done all I need to do in Guilin, and I am quite tired of studying, you know after doing it for my entire life up to this point. It is time for something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have basically no idea what this trip is going to be. The plan is no plan. There are cities I want to hit. Things I want to do, but it is all up for change at a moment's notice. This is how I want it to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goals for this trip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Return home safe (I am ever the pragmatic)&lt;br /&gt;2. Ride a camel &lt;br /&gt;3. See something more beautiful than I have ever seen before &lt;br /&gt;4. Make a new friend worth knowing&lt;br /&gt;5. Dumbfound a Chinese person with something I do&lt;br /&gt;6. Dumfound myself with something crazy or stupid that I do&lt;br /&gt;7. Return to my old favorites&lt;br /&gt;8. Make a new favorite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(It doesn't need to be a goal to see a something dumbfounding done by a Chinese person, that pretty much happens every hour of the day when you travel here.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lady on the train next to me just up and grabbed the baby from a dad in the row in front of us. The baby was ok with it for about five seconds and then was like "uhhh you are not my mom, and your e-reader is not that cool please give me back" and started crying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am starting to get to the point where I don't actively notice that I am the only westerner in a place. It is my constant state and will be for the next few days more likely than not.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>