<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Changsha and Shaoshan</title>
  <slug>changsha-and-shaoshan</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-06-29 23:59:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Picking up from the last post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting off the bullet train I got in a cab, and because the cabbie was trying to drive around aimlessly it seemed I got on the subway. From the subway I walked about a mile and a half with all of my stuff on my back. I then wandered through neighborhoods trying to find my hostel. I got a great view of real Chinese life, but it was tiring with 60 some odd pounds on my back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually I got to the hostel, after some bad directions from a security guard at a hotel that was literally two minutes' walk from where I was going. I checked in and just sat in the lobby to recover for a few minutes and use the Wi-Fi. After a few minutes some other travelers called the hostel and the staff attempted to talk to them in English. I offered to assist because it didn't seem to be going well. However, the connection dropped a few times. I tried to tell them to get to a certain place and that I would hop on a bus to come get them and bring them to the hostel. I gave the front desk my number if they came back. I met up with the girls later and went to a bar, apparently the front desk didn't give them my number. Oh well, they made it in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My day was basically wandering around the area and taking pictures. I also found a little pool hall by the college campus nearby and played a few games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I almost forgot my most frustrating moment of the day. When I went to the bar with the girls from the hostel we arrived and ordered food and drinks at the bar. After we sat down a waiter came over and asked in English if we had ordered. I sort of mumbled out some Chinese saying we had already ordered. He responded by saying, "why in Chinese?" (basically that exact broken English sentence). OH I DON'T KNOW I AM WORKING MY BUTT OFF TRYING TO LEARN YOUR LANGUAGE YOU INCONSIDERATE (insert your favorite insult here). I understand that they have the fun western vibe going on in the bar and my presence as an American there trying to speak Chinese goes against the theme of the bar, but come on give me a break. It's these sorts of moments that are very discouraging when studying a language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning was the couple hour train from Changsha to Shaoshan to visit Mao Tze Dong's home town. The train ride I was mostly left alone by the other travelers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I got there, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know where I was going so I went over to the little China Post stands that are everywhere and asked if I could find a map. She of course had one, for a few kuai's fee. I sat down on a bench, and a man walked up and asked where I was going. I told him where I wanted to go sort of on the map. He was obviously one of the guys who drives people around in his cab for a living. I asked how much, and he gave me what seemed like a reasonable price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While in the car he then, like a good businessman, tried to start up selling me. He offered two things, one to call one of his friends to be my tour guide, I declined on that. He then offered for 100 kaui to be my driver for the day. It took me a moment to understand what he meant, but when I figured it out I agreed. The first place he took me seemed a bit like a tourist trap. I paid 60 kuai to get in and there didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be anything around. The cabbie probably got a cut of my admission fee. Eventually I found some things in the park and in general it was a nice place to walk around so I was not upset, other than the idea that someone thought they had done me over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is actually where I saw the most interesting, or disturbing thing for the day. There in the park was a little temple to Mao. I saw people actually bowing down to a statue of Mao. The whole place was set up a little bit like a Buddhist temple. In the middle was the golden colored statue inside a glass box. They said no pictures, so I wasn't able to get any that captured the weirdness that I felt in that moment. Not something I am likely to forget any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next stop was Mao's old house. It was exactly what you would expect. A half an hour line of people with one foreigner. The house seemed very well preserved. As opposed to what I have seen previously with Chinese tourist attractions, this one seemed very authentic. It was an actual piece of the life that a man lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there I went to lunch, again the driver clearly took me to somewhere he was going to get something out of the deal. The food was expensive and he got to eat for free in the back. I did them all over by ordering the cheapest thing on the menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch I was waiting around for the driver to finish eating and a group of twenty-somethings locals came and invited me to come sit with them. They tried to get me to drink some beer with them or eat their food. Interesting moment, a little strange, got some practice speaking Chinese. These two days has certainly been a test of my Chinese so far, seeing how I have seen about five other foreigners since I left Guilin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I of course made another avoidable flaw on my way back to Changsha, I bought a bus ticket to the wrong station. I ended up going to the one that I came into town on, which was way out of town. I didn't think about it. Such is life. So after a big bus and then some city buses later, I arrived back at the hostel. The rest of the night was spend hanging out in the lobby talking with one of the guys staying there. He was also a programmer. This as opposed to every other conversation I have had in my travels here actually had some substance as opposed to all pleasantries and small talk.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>