<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Qingdao</title>
  <slug>qingdao</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-07-11 10:53:10</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;After arriving and checking in at the hostel I didn't accomplish to much adventuring. I sat in the caf&amp;eacute; and blogged and I skyped with mom and Mollie for a bit. hadn&amp;rsquo;t called any of my family members since I was in Guilin, so it was very nice to hear a familiar voice. In the first 24 hours I talked to My mom, my dad, Mollie, Grandma Sissy and my aunt Robin and uncle Bill (who I haven't talked to in over a year.) With my homesickness dealt with for the moment I proceeded to my room to take a nap. I intended to take an hour nap and go sightseeing after the nap. I accidentally slept for three and half hours. As my mom always says "you don't wake a sleeping baby." I decided that for the few days that I was in Qingdao I was going to be as relaxed as possible, so I booked a private room. The first night it was unavailable so my first night's rest wasn't exactly restful due to the massive amount of snoring the guy below me was doing. Needless to say I was a bit tired. So the nap was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeling recharged I set out to find food. I walked down the street a bit aimlessly. I almost walked by a street, but decided to walk down it because it looked fairly interesting. I was of course rewarded as interesting Chinese streets often reward people who wander down them. I was greeted after one block by a massive street market with all sorts of foods, spices, lots of live fish and plenty of sights and smells. I unfortunately didn't have my good camera so I didn't get any terribly good pictures of my first walk down the street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This continued to be a small problem because I just kept walking and walking. I walked down the coastline for the remainder of the day. The beach was not particularly clean and was way too crowded so I stayed on the streets mostly. In total I probably walked around six miles. I ended up at Chinese Marine University. When I was walking on the campus I walked in and kept walking, I was tired and thought that I might not find a way out and would have to backtrack. This would have been entirely unacceptable given the state of my feet at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a bit of a rest to sit and watch people playing basketball. They weren't especially talented as I recall. Then after a bit more I popped out of the campus. I was greeted at the gate by a guy selling notebooks out of the back of his van. I of course was suckered in to buying three. I bought a Starry Night Van Gogh one, and a funny Chinglish one to give to someone back home, haven&amp;rsquo;t decided who the lucky friend is. I asked the salesman what bus I should take back to the railway station, which was the easiest way to get back to my hostel probably. He told me line 2, I don't think line 2 even came out to where we were. So I just walked to the nearest bus stop. Luckily all roads lead to the Qingdao railway station, so I got on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the station I headed back to the hostel. I was still fairly tired and I wanted to stop at a caf&amp;eacute;, and almost as soon as I had the thought one appeared. I wanted to just relax with a cup of tea or something. Well it ended up being the "or something" because a pot of tea was 80 kuai. So I scanned the menu some, and finally the manager recommended what ended up being a lemon crushed ice drink. It was nice, not what I was expecting, but very good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The caf&amp;eacute; was awesome though, they were playing my favorite Yiruma album, it was quiet, and some guy brought his really cute dog. I sat listened to the music, journaled and just thanked God for this brief moment that was pure bliss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of dogs I completely forgot to mention that I was about to be killed by one when I was walking on the beach. I was listening to music, apparently too loudly for the continuance of my lineage. I was reaching down to pick up a shell for Mollie, yes Mollie you almost got me killed because you requested a Chinese shell, and all the sudden I see this flash of brown in the corner of my eye and a bark that was way too close to me. I looked up and it was not the wild stray beast that I expected it would be but a beautiful German Shepard with a collar on and an owner yelling to him from up above. The dog was having the time of his life. He was dashing about picking up rocks with his mouth that he had no business trying to pick up, quite comical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing left of note for the day was that the guy underneath me snored in a way that made me concerned for his health and my sanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr width="100%" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next two days were spend in classic Jackson fashion, hanging out with someone three times my age. He was cooler than you, my dear reader, and I put together (obviously the judgment of coolness of is determined by me, and also it's not your fault I didn't bring much to the table in coolness factor for our team). His resume of coolness:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fully done Wikipedia page about him. (This is a joke. However, his life story seems to check out.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Married to a well-known poet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professor of Literature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on a photography book in China on his summer breaks. &lt;br /&gt;War correspondent and photographer most notably in civil wars in Spanish speaking countries (where Americans were often seen as the enemy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not going to recount too much of we did because it was basically just walking around Qingdao taking pictures of stuff and chatting. The most interesting thing about being around his was his ability to just make friends with anyone. It was incredible how close to people he would get to take pictures of them. He would walk back into alleys or spots I just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t think were appropriate for me to go into just start talking to them. His Chinese was good, but not perfect. That was even more amazing, a lot of his ability to make people comfortable was the fact that being in his presence you can tell that "he is harmless." Also one is probably not skittish of people when you are 99% sure they have no intention of killing you when you have had plenty of the opposite.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just walking around with him one can tell that he sees the world in a different way than the rest of us. He described himself as an ocular omnivore. His eyes are as astute&amp;nbsp;and attuned&amp;nbsp;to the colors, shapes and light around him as a chef is to the taste and texture of food. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, he is the kind of person that just being around one wants to immediately go chase after their dreams. I also am not going to share with you all my dreams until I have achieved them. That's just my style. However, he definitely sparked some ideas in my head and rekindled some old ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest thing I learned from my time with him was that I often sell myself short. I am always saying that I don't think I can do anything important or that my perspective on life is not interesting or worthwhile. Neither of these two thoughts are correct.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>