<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Big Brother Has a Different Face</title>
  <slug>big-brother-has-a-different-face</slug>
  <author>Jackson Hayes</author>
  <pubDate>2014-05-26 01:34:29</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-08-04 01:55:34</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;In one of my all time favorite books, Orwell's "1984", a name is given to the idea that in the future we will be constantly monitored&amp;mdash;that name is "Big Brother." For those of you who have not read the book (presumably having lived under a rock or glued to your telescreen watching reality TV your whole life) the people of Oceania are constantly monitored by the&amp;nbsp;government for "thought crimes," which are thinking about anything the government does not want you to. The net result of this monitoring is a society that is completely and utterly dominated by the government and incapable of original thought. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History has not panned out exactly how Orwell envisioned, but the end result is fast becoming the same. Today it is not&amp;nbsp;governments of the world that are doing the most disruptive monitoring of the general public (they probably do the biggest bulk of monitoring and there monitoring has the biggest potential of creating an Orwellian dystopian future but that is not the point of this rant) it is companies like Facebook and Google. These companies are fast becoming the owners of our minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most recent example: &lt;a href="http://readwrite.com/2014/05/21/facebook-spying-mobile-microphone-music-tv#disqus_anchor"&gt;Facebook Can Now Spy On Your Surroundings Via Your Phone's Microphone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't disagree with companies collecting data about online users to serve advertisements on principle; this practice is basically what made the&amp;nbsp;Internet a viable place for people to provide interesting content for free. Without these ads everything on the web would be pay-to-play (another buzz word of today's web space that I will not go into). What I do mind is the slow and subtle way it is changing the way we view our privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a experiment that, and we all know the result:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk into any room and see how many people are using an Internet connected device. In the sitting room of my hostel it is 5 for 5. We are all being quantified, correlated and then understood. We don't know by whom, and that to me is terrifying.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People do question these things when they come out and try to warn people, but in general they are ignored by the vast majority of people who are drowned in the media ocean in which we live. The majority of&amp;nbsp;Internet users just use whatever is the default setting on whatever device or service that they are using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is worse is this scenario that we find ourselves in is not that we have some oppressive state that is pushing this monitoring on us. We are forcing it upon each other with the new social contract of the Internet. We spend so much of our time on the&amp;nbsp;Internet just seeing what other people are doing. Instead of going out and doing things we go around taking pictures so that other people can see what we are doing. With this increase of self monitoring we are creating a society that has is extremely hyper-sensitive to difference&amp;nbsp;among people. Yes I am making a bold statement the world that we think we live that is supposed to becoming all embracing is not that at all. It is a system that is geared to make everyone the same media consuming drone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where do we draw the line? I for one am already drawing a line in the sand. I am not going to let anything constantly monitor me unless I want it. I will not be letting Facebook or any other service listen into my conversations on what TV show I am watching as the default setting. Keeping control of your own freedoms on the Internet is an active process. Don't let any new world voodo marketing fool you the tech giants are creating the potential for us to lose the control of some of or all of the freedom of our minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enlightenment is man's release from his self-incurred tutelage. Tutelage is man's inability to make use of his understanding without direction from another. Self-incurred is this tutelage when its cause lies not in lack of reason but in lack of resolution and courage to use it without direction from another." -Emanuel Kant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are constantly be directed. Only a select few of us will be truly Enlightened as Kant defines it if we keep allowing entities outside ourselves to control what we see on a minute to minute basis.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>